<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright [year] [name] -->
<component type="desktop-application">
    <id>io.github.qrrk.Catapult</id>
    <name>Catapult</name>

    <summary>A cross-platform launcher for Cataclysm: DDA and BN</summary>

    <metadata_license>CC-BY-SA-4.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>MIT</project_license>

    <developer_name>qrrk</developer_name>

    <url type="homepage">https://github.com/qrrk/Catapult</url>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/qrrk/Catapult/issues</url>

    <recommends>
        <control>keyboard</control>
    </recommends>
    <supports>
        <control>console</control>
        <control>gamepad</control>
    </supports>

    <description>
        <p>
            Catapult is a cross-platform launcher and content manager for Cataclysm: Dark Days Ahead
            and Cataclysm: Bright Nights. It is in part inspired by earlier versions of Rémy Roy's launcher.
        </p>
        <p>Features:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Automatic game download and installation (stable or experimental releases).</li>
            <li>Ability to install multiple versions of the game and switch between them.</li>
            <li>Updating the game while preserving user data (saved games, settings, mods, etc).</li>
            <li>Mod management: Kenan Modpack download and complete or selective installation.</li>
            <li>Automatic download and installation of soundpacks.</li>
            <li>Customization of game fonts.</li>
            <li>Saved game backups.</li>
            <li>Multilingual interface.</li>
            <li>
                Good support for HiDPI displays: UI is automatically scaled with screen DPI,
                with ability to adjust the scale manually.
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>
            Cataclysm: Dark Days Ahead is a turn-based survival game set in a post-apocalyptic
            world. Scavenge, explore, craft, build, farm, repair and modify vehicles, install bionics,
            mutate, defend against zombies and countless other monstrosities - all in a limitless,
            procedurally generated world!
        </p>
        <p>
            Cataclysm: Bright Nights. Reject pedantry, embrace !!fun!!. This fork takes the game back
            to its sci-fi roguelike roots and reverts many controversial changes by the DDA team
            (pockets, proficiencies, freezing, and more). Special attention is paid to combat, game
            balance and pacing.
        </p>
    </description>

    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image>https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/19731636/183306856-65921632-0173-4a66-9632-a5ba1285943d.png</image>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>

    <releases>
        <release version="22.08a" date="2022-08-07">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <p>
                            It is now possible to have multiple versions of the game installed at the
                            same time and switch between them.
                        </p>
                        <ul>
                            <li>
                                To install an additional copy of the game, simply uncheck the
                                "Update current active install" checkbox.
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                Out of all installed copies of the game, one is always considered
                                "active", i.e. being used at the moment. This version will be started
                                when you click Play/Resume.
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                (!) Keep in mind that the userdata folder (containing saves, game settings
                                and so on) is shared between all game installs, so beware of breakages or
                                data corruption when switching between too-distant versions (e.g. stable
                                and experimental).
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        UI scaling was reworked once again. The 2D scaling mode just didn't look good
                        enough despite my efforts, so I bit the bullet and implemented proper scaling
                        for UI themes. Finally, crisp text and outlines at any scale!
                    </li>
                    <li>Spanish translation by @JuaniElias.</li>
                    <li>Polish translation by @nheve.</li>
                    <li>Added the soundpack CC-Sounds.</li>
                    <li>You can now set whether to keep the launcher open after starting the game.</li>
                    <li>
                        An unofficial AUR package is now available (catapult-bin,
                        maintained by @AriaMoradi).
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="22.03c" date="2022-03-23">
            <description>
                <p>
                    This is a big one. If you are updating from an earlier version,
                    read the warning below!
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <p>
                            User data (saves, settings, custom mods, sounds, etc.) is now stored
                            separately from game installation itself.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            This means no files need to be "migrated" to the new version when updating,
                            since only the game itself is deleted and replaced, not user data.
                            Consequently, all migration-related settings have been removed.
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            (!) Important: This change breaks compatibility with previous versions of the
                            launcher. If you are updating your existing setup, a manual intervention is
                            required:
                        </p>
                        <ul>
                            <li>
                                Move config, font, graveyard, memorial, mods, save, sound, templates
                                from dda/current to dda/userdata.
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                If you have any custom tilesets, move them from dda/current/gfx
                                to dda/userdata/gfx.
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                        <p>
                            The paths above are for C:DDA. For C:BN, use bn/current/*
                            and bn/userdata/* instead.
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        You can now quick-load your last played world in one click, skipping the main menu.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Czech language has been added by @Elinvynia.
                    </li>
                    <li>Interface language can now be changed without restarting the launcher.</li>
                    <li>
                        Four extra themes have been added. Catapult now has 3 dark and 2 light
                        themes to choose from.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        A compressed format is now used for themes. This made the app smaller and
                        faster to load, even with all the new themes.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="22.03b" date="2022-03-12">
            <description>
                <p>We already have another localization: @raylemon has translated Catapult into French!</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Added French translation.</li>
                    <li>
                        Translation files have been reorganized. Previously, almost all translation data
                        was stored in one large file, which was getting increasingly unwieldy as more
                        languages were added. Now it is much more granular and manageable.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="22.03a" date="2022-03-09">
            <description>
                <p>
                    In less than two weeks since translation infrastructure was added,
                    we already have the first contribution! Thank you, @dyxxzgc!
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Added Simplified Chinese translation carried out by @dyxxzgc.</li>
                    <li>
                        Executable size has slightly increased due to additional
                        font required for Chinese.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p>
                    Note: there are no other changes whatsoever compared to the previous release.
                    If you aren't interested in the Chinese translation, you don't have to update.
                </p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="22.02b" date="2022-02-26">
            <description>
                <p>A major update that introduces translations and improved UI.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        Translations have been implemented. Now new languages can be added simply by
                        editing the CSV files in Excel, LibreOffice, or even in the Notepad.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Russian language is now supported in the launcher. Right now this is the only
                        language besides English that's been added, but hopefully more will
                        be contributed in the future.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p>Also, multiple UI improvements have been made:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        UI scaling was handed off to the engine instead of essentially micro-managing
                        the sizes of all elements from code. Now Catapult uses the 2d viewport scaling
                        mode of Godot, which also isn't perfect (see below), but it makes the UI look very
                        consistent at different scales and gets rid of occasional oddly sized elements and
                        visual glitches.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Many UI tweaks were done, mainly to make the interface more compact.
                        Font was made smaller, element spacing was reduced in many places.
                        If you had a custom scale set, you may have to re-adjust it.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Launcher window is now resizable, which was made easy by the new scaling method.
                        Window size and position are remembered between sessions.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p>Known issues:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Text may look slightly blurry at non-integer scales.</li>
                    <li>
                        UI scales below 100% look bad. I can only hope that barely anyone will have
                        to use them, now that the window is more compact.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="22.02a" date="2022-02-20">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        The first iteration of savegame backups is now live, thanks to xuvatilavv!
                        For now, backups can only be done manually. Beware that when a backup is restored,
                        it replaces all contents of the save folder!
                    </li>
                    <li>Changelog link was moved to a more prominent location.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="21.12c" date="2021-12-24">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Added 0.F-3 stable release on Windows.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="21.12b" date="2021-12-21">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Changelog now loads faster and works a lot more reliably.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="21.12a" date="2021-12-17">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Added a game changelog compiled from merged pull requests (thanks to Inglonias).</li>
                    <p>
                        Data retrieval from GitHub doesn't always work reliably, especially for DDA,
                        due to the sheer number of merged PRs in this repository. If you encounter this,
                        please don't report it as a bug: it's on GitHub's side, and we are aware of it.
                        We hope this problem is temporary.
                    </p>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="21.11b" date="2021-11-22">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Fixed Kenan modpack installation again.</li>
                    <li>Added an option to include archived mods when installing Kenan modpack.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="21.11a" date="2021-11-13">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Fixed Kenan modpack installation.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="21.09f" date="2021-09-23">
            <description>
                <p>
                    This time, a partial rework of mod management. It addresses the problem of being
                    unable to install mods that come with the game but are marked as "obsolete".
                    Such mods are no longer considered by the launcher as "already installed", letting
                    you install a second (hopefully updated) copy of them with a modified ID
                    (to avoid errors).
                </p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="21.09e" date="2021-09-19">
            <description>
                <p>
                    This is the first big feature update. Catapult now lets you customize in-game fonts
                    by selecting from several hand-picked typefaces built into the launcher.
                    This will be especially handy for owners of 2K/4K monitors.
                </p>
                <p>
                    If you've customized game fonts manually before, you'll know that for some fonts
                    you need to find a good combination of font width, height and size by trial and error.
                    For fonts offered in Catapult, this work has already been done, and correct values
                    will be put in automatically when you assign the font. Font sizes for UI, map and
                    overmap can also be adjusted right from the launcher.
                </p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="21.09d" date="2021-09-13">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Fixed extraction errors when the path contains spaces.</li>
                    <li>UI scaling tweaks.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="21.09c" date="2021-09-12">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Added a button to quickly open the game folder.</li>
                    <li>Switched from Powershell to bundled UnZip for archive extraction, so Windows 7 is now truly supported.</li>
                    <li>Updated some UI icons.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="21.09b" date="2021-09-10">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>Better debug mode for troubleshooting.</li>
                    <li>One small UI fix.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="21.09a" date="2021-09-09">
            <description>
                <p>The first public release of the launcher.</p>
            </description>
        </release>
    </releases>

    <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.qrrk.Catapult.desktop</launchable>

    <languages>
        <lang>en</lang>
        <lang>cs</lang>
        <lang>es</lang>
        <lang>fr</lang>
        <lang>pl</lang>
        <lang>ru</lang>
        <lang>tr</lang>
        <lang>zh</lang>
    </languages>

    <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
        <content_attribute id="violence-fantasy">intense</content_attribute>
        <content_attribute id="violence-bloodshed">intense</content_attribute>
        <content_attribute id="violence-desecration">intense</content_attribute>
        <content_attribute id="violence-slavery">intense</content_attribute>
        <content_attribute id="drugs-alcohol">moderate</content_attribute>
        <content_attribute id="drugs-narcotics">moderate</content_attribute>
        <content_attribute id="drugs-tobacco">moderate</content_attribute>
        <content_attribute id="sex-nudity">intense</content_attribute>
        <content_attribute id="sex-themes">moderate</content_attribute>
        <content_attribute id="language-profanity">moderate</content_attribute>
        <content_attribute id="language-humor">mild</content_attribute>
      </content_rating>    
</component>
